# **Tonyo Godson Pupere**

I am a proactive, smart, motivated software engineer and leader with good development experience. I have joined in the development of software solutions for business use cases from conceptualization to deployment. I am a proficient Android Developer. Software I have built includes Business Tech solutions such as Paysure Mobile, Aqua, Pigtiles, etc.

### Experience

**3LINE CARD MANAGEMENT,** Lagos — *Software Engineer* 

SEPTEMBER 2022 - DATE

- Experience building Android apps with Kotlin/Java using the Android SDK.
- Good understanding of the android app lifecycle and common design patterns (MVVM, MVP) for building and structuring apps from data layer all the way up to the UI.
- Strong understanding of REST APIs, JSON, HTTP Requests, Retrofit
- Experience working with ROOM Database.
- Familiar with Jetpack Components
- Good understanding of Dependency Injection and libraries like DAGGER HILT
- Experience with using version control like git

#### **DECAGON,** Lagos — Software Engineer

**OCTOBER 2019 - AUGUST 2022** 

- I am responsible for translating code into user-friendly applications.
- I collaborate with other members of the team to develop functional mobile applications while working in a fastpaced environment.
- I work with application programming interfaces (APIs) to support mobile functionality while keeping up to date with terminology, concepts and best practices for coding mobile apps.
- I contribute to the design, testing, releasing and support of the application.

## **Education**

**Niger Delta University** — BSc. Computer Science

(Second Class Upper Division)

**SEPTEMBER 2010 - MAY 2015** 

Niger Delta University,

Wilberforce Island, Bayelsa State,

Nigeria

7, Asajon way, Sangotedo, Lagos, Nigeria.

Phone: +2348138499363

Email: tonyo.pupere@gmail.com

## **Technologies**

- Kotlin/Java
  - Room Database
  - JetPack DataStore
  - Coroutines
  - Navigation Component
  - Dependency Injection
  - View Binding
  - MVVM Architecture
  - ViewModel
  - LiveData
- Figma
- Version Control with Git and Github
- Jira
- Postman